<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>sciman.info</title>
  <subtitle>Thoughts and writing from Sciman101</subtitle>
  <link href="https://sciman.info" />
  <updated>2024-10-06T04:03:47.282Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Sciman101</name>
  </author>
  <id>https://sciman.info</id>

  
  
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <category type="blog" />
    <title>Blog - Ricket's Computer Trouble released!</title>
    <link href="/blog/rickets-computer-trouble/" />
    <id>/blog/rickets-computer-trouble/</id>
    <updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>
      Getting back into the swing of making games
    </summary>
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <category type="blog" />
    <title>Blog - Resurrecting a Cricut Mini</title>
    <link href="/blog/resurrecting-a-cricut-mini/" />
    <id>/blog/resurrecting-a-cricut-mini/</id>
    <updated>2024-04-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>
      Breathing life back into a dead vinyl cutter
    </summary>
  </entry>
  
  

  
  
  <entry>
    <category type="writing" />
    <title>Writing - Stargazing</title>
    <link href="/writing/stargazing/" />
    <id>/writing/stargazing/</id>
    <updated>2024-06-29T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>"I just want *one thing* to be easy." Pitch grumbled. "That's not so much, is it? I'm not asking too much that I want being able to *exist* to be easy." She spoke with a venom in her voice that had been distilled from years of experience.
</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <category type="writing" />
    <title>Writing - Sentient Water Filter</title>
    <link href="/writing/sentient-water-filter/" />
    <id>/writing/sentient-water-filter/</id>
    <updated>2023-10-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>So, of course, they made something with openAware. Why wouldn't they? Everyone was using openAware. Google shoved it into their search engine, Boston Dynamics had Atlas competing on Wipeout with it, even a company like Milestone was thinking about integrating it into the Mi-90, and Milestone was notoriously behind the times. openAware was the trend, and if staying trendy meant they could keep funding the fleet, that was the way to go.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <category type="writing" />
    <title>Writing - Reuinted</title>
    <link href="/writing/reunited/" />
    <id>/writing/reunited/</id>
    <updated>2023-12-25T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>"But then... you’re not dead. You were alive, on the mainland. Mingling with humans.” The smile disappeared. “You broke our hearts, and just as quickly went and broke our law. Our way of living. But, despite that...” She sighed, tired. ”I can't hold it against you. You were doing the same thing we were - you had moved on, you found a new life, as much as it goes against what we believe in.”
For just a moment, a smile returned to her chest mouth.
”I like to think you were happy."</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <category type="writing" />
    <title>Writing - Pitch Black</title>
    <link href="/writing/pitch-black/" />
    <id>/writing/pitch-black/</id>
    <updated>2023-11-16T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>She frowned. This tasted really bad. She wasn't buying this snack again in the future.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <category type="writing" />
    <title>Writing - Not Built for This</title>
    <link href="/writing/not-built-for-this/" />
    <id>/writing/not-built-for-this/</id>
    <updated>2024-03-25T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>Her voice trailed off. Nothing sounded right. She imagined Ru-B hearing what she had to say, and the way she'd respond. That momentary flicker in the LEDs of her eyes when she got angry. The feeling of a wall building itself up between the two of them. Cutting off the only other person that felt real. She shook her head, and tried to focus on her little fidget. When suddenly, there came a banging from the front door.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <category type="writing" />
    <title>Writing - Diner Date</title>
    <link href="/writing/diner-date/" />
    <id>/writing/diner-date/</id>
    <updated>2024-07-14T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary>At the counter, Moby and Ru-B sat besides one another. The former scanned the menu, carefully considering each option, quietly practicing the eventual order to the waiter in her head. The latter thumbed through with lazy disinterest, more focused on Moby than anything on offer.
</summary>
  </entry>
  

</feed>